<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports analytics on Under The Hood</title>
    <link>/tags/sports-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports analytics on Under The Hood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sports-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to know the fitzRoy package (AFL game statistics)</title>
      <link>/2019/01/12/getting-to-know-the-fitzroy-package-afl-game-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/12/getting-to-know-the-fitzroy-package-afl-game-statistics/</guid>
      <description>(source: Wikimedia)I shifted across the ditch early in 2018 to take up a role with High Performance Sport New Zealand. Remarkably, the one-year anniversary of our arrival here is right on the door step; I’ve learned so much in that time, particularly around qualitative methods and analyses. I enjoy the richness of insight that can be drawn from analysing text data, but a part of me does miss getting to work with numbers as much as I used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text mining of Wimbledon tweets using rtweet and tidytext</title>
      <link>/2018/07/20/text-mining-of-wimbledon-tweets-using-rtweet-and-tidytext/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/20/text-mining-of-wimbledon-tweets-using-rtweet-and-tidytext/</guid>
      <description>New job, new skillsThis year, I started in a new role as Senior Insights Researcher at High Performance Sport New Zealand. For me, one of the big drawcards of this role was the opportunity to learn and grow my skills and competencies as a performance sport professional.
Our team regularly deals with qualitative data, so as an applied sport scientist with a strongly quantitative training, it has been a steep learning curve but also enjoyable to open my mind up to different ways of thinking and knowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My coding origin story</title>
      <link>/2017/10/01/my-coding-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/01/my-coding-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked questions about how long I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for, how I got started, whether I have completed any formal studies in programming / computer science, and so on. The reality is that my path is far from linear. Most of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to date has been more opportunistic than strategic, curiosity-driven rather than being part of a master plan to acquire professional skills for the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>