<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Under The Hood</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Under The Hood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Text mining of Wimbledon tweets using rtweet and tidytext</title>
      <link>/2018/07/20/text-mining-of-wimbledon-tweets-using-rtweet-and-tidytext/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/20/text-mining-of-wimbledon-tweets-using-rtweet-and-tidytext/</guid>
      <description>New job, new skillsThis year, I started in a new role as Senior Insights Researcher at High Performance Sport New Zealand. For me, one of the big drawcards of this role was the opportunity to learn and grow my skills and competencies as a performance sport professional.
Our team regularly deals with qualitative data, so as an applied sport scientist with a strongly quantitative training, it has been a steep learning curve but also enjoyable to open my mind up to different ways of thinking and knowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part III - Comparison by discipline</title>
      <link>/2018/01/04/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/04/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-3/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the third in a series - to get up to speed, have a read through the first post and the second post. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedLoad up the data and the libraries as we’ve done before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part II - Job seniority</title>
      <link>/2018/01/03/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/03/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-2/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the second in a series; click here to read the first post if you haven’t already done so. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden Oakley published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedWe’ll load the cleaned data in and load the necessary libraries as we did in the first post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part I - An initial exploration</title>
      <link>/2018/01/02/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/02/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The backstoryIt’s a touchy subject for many. Yet this question—how much do you get paid?—is at the core of the online questionnaire that was recently administered by Aiden Oakley (@ajoakley on Twitter). And it is a question that was willingly answered by over 100 sport scientists and strength &amp;amp; conditioning coaches who currently work for football (soccer) clubs in the UK.
Why?
This job advert says it all…
This is shocking!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My coding origin story</title>
      <link>/2017/10/01/my-coding-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/01/my-coding-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked questions about how long I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for, how I got started, whether I have completed any formal studies in programming / computer science, and so on. The reality is that my path is far from linear. Most of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to date has been more opportunistic than strategic, curiosity-driven rather than being part of a master plan to acquire professional skills for the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>