<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football on Under The Hood</title>
    <link>/tags/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Football on Under The Hood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part VI - Next steps</title>
      <link>/2018/01/09/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/09/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is the sixth and final in a series - go on and read the first, second, third, fourth, and fifth posts for background. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Ways to improve the questionnaire  Ask participants to identify the nature of their work in terms of whether they are full-time, part-time, casual, or volunteer / intern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part V - Credential creep</title>
      <link>/2018/01/08/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/08/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-5/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the fifth in a series - go on and read the first, second, third, and fourth posts for background. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedLoad the data and the libraries as we’ve done before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part IV - Academies by category status</title>
      <link>/2018/01/06/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/06/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-4/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the fourth in a series - I suggest reading the first, second, and third posts for background. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedLoad the data and the libraries as we’ve done before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part II - Job seniority</title>
      <link>/2018/01/04/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/04/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-2/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the second in a series; click here to read the first post if you haven’t already done so. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden Oakley published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedWe’ll load the cleaned data in and load the necessary libraries as we did in the first post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part I - An initial exploration</title>
      <link>/2018/01/02/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/02/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The backstoryIt’s a touchy subject for many. Yet this question—how much do you get paid?—is at the core of the online questionnaire that was recently administered by Aiden Oakley (@ajoakley on Twitter). And it is a question that was willingly answered by over 100 sport scientists and strength &amp;amp; conditioning coaches who currently work for football (soccer) clubs in the UK.
Why?
This job advert says it all…
This is shocking!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much do you get paid? Part III - Comparison by discipline</title>
      <link>/2017/01/05/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/05/how-much-do-you-get-paid-part-3/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis post is the third in a series - to get up to speed, here are some links so you can read the first post and the second post. In this series, I will show how I created the plots that Aiden published on Twitter here and here, alongside some commentary about the choices I made throughout the process and my own interpretations of the results.
Getting startedLoad up the data and the libraries as we’ve done before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>